Hello, in this task about flat state diagrams
we are given a short story of a puzzle of
a family trying to cross the river with a
boat.
In the first part of the task, we are asked
to give a static model of the story depicted
as a graph, specifically.
That is, we need to think about which people,
objects, properties and relationships between
them are important in order to solve the puzzle
and which are not.
I am going to assume you already read the
story so I am just going to skip over it now.
And mark parts that are important to the puzzle
and therefore should be included in our model
and talk about the parts that might seem important
but really are not,
at least in terms of our puzzle here.
So, in the first sentence we have a lot of
set up information about where we are, who's
involved and what they are doing.
Most importantly here, we have the father
and his 2 daughters.
These are the people trying to cross the river.
And we know it is a sunny Saturday morning
in October, they are 31 years old and 9 years
old respectively and they hike through the
Lower Rhine area.
All of that information could be included
in the model,
but since none of these really changes how
the puzzle is solved,
we are not going to include it here.
Next note is, there is no bridge on the river.
This might seem very important,
because this is the whole reason why they
are trying to cross the river with the boat,
but it doesn’t really change the puzzle.
Because the set up its, okay; they are trying
to cross the river over the boat doesn’t
really matter if there is a bridge 10 meters
away or 100 meters away, not.
We are still going to try to cross the river
with the boat, so this is also superfluous
information that does not need to be in the
model necessarily.
Luckily on the bank of the river, the family
meets an old fisherman with a boat.
This is the fourth actor or the third actor
if you view the daughter separately and he
has a boat.
This is important information because another
actor that is involved in the puzzle.
He needs to cross back and forth as well,
and the boat is the object of transportation.
So, this is important, the fact that it is
small.
But we are getting more information on that
further ahead.
The fisherman agrees to lend them his boat.
Okay, it is just large enough to carry either a single
adult or up to two children. This is critical
information because this is basically the
crux of the whole puzzle. Because not everybody
can cross at once. That would kind of make
this puzzle a little bit too simple.
So, it can just carry a single adult or up to
two children.
So, this is definitely information that needs
to be in our model.
Both the adult and the children are able to
row, once again, this might seem very important;
but since there is nobody involved, who cannot
row and everybody can row, it is not really
an aspect that would fit well into the model
here.
Because then we would have a note that says “okay,
people can row and that would connect to every
other actor”. That is not really helpful
here, we are just going to assume this,
"okay, everybody can row, everybody in our model
can row", we do not need to specifically add
this to the model.
What is important, however, is that the boat
will not move on its own.
Because then we could just send the boat back
and that would once again make the puzzle
kind of trivial.
Because then, two children can cross over,
just push the boat back and then a single
adult can push the boat back.
And the fisherman just stays there.
The boat pushed back again that would make
this puzzle a little too easy.
So, this is definitely critical information
as well.
How can the family cross the river with the
boat?
This is the question the puzzle is asking
and importantly here at the end the fisherman
wants to be back on the same bank as he was
in the beginning, with his boat of course.
So, we somehow need to put in our model that
the boat belongs to the fisherman, and he
wants it back with him on the side he started
off.
So, now that we have marked all the important
information in our story,
we can start drawing our graph.
We are going to start by just revolving everything
around the boat.
You can do this differently and of course
this is left intentionally vague here. (Depiction
as a graph, it does not say what graph
it is.)
The important part of this task is for you
to think about what is important to be involved
in the model such as this and what is not.
How the graph looks in the end does not quite
matter as much as what information the graph
contains.
So, do not worry about if your graph ends
up looking differently, it very well might
look very differently.
As long as the information that is important
is in there and there is not too much superfluous
information you are going to be fine.
So, for my graph I am going to start by putting
in note for the boat itself.
Because everything kind of revolves around
the boat, how many people can ride in it etcetera,
where the boat is going to end up and where
the people are going to end up.
So, I am going to start by just drawing the
note for the boat.
Next up we have two sides of the river.
So, we have the gold side, we are going to
call it the other side here where the father
and his two daughters want to end up at and
the starting side, where the boat and the
fisherman need to end up in the end.
Because they are going to stay in the starting
side as given in the story.
Next up, of course, we have our actor, we have
the father, and we have his two daughters.
You might separate the daughters into two
nodes here,
but that is not strictly necessary here.
Because in terms of the puzzle, the daughters
are identical basically.
They even have the same age might be a bit
reductive to think about it person as having
properties and two children being identical.
But just looking at this in terms of the puzzle,
the daughters are identical and can be combined
to a single note here, or of course we can
put two separate notes.
Next up we have the fisherman.
Of course, on the boat.
And he is critical to the story.
Because he is going to be riding back and
forth as well.
Then, of course, we have all the information
about the properties between them.
We have the fisherman fit alone into the boat.
So, I am just drawing an arrow here pointing
at the boat and saying with an annotation
“the fisherman fits alone into the boat”.
So, that kind of implies that can cross alone
and nobody else fits in.
Next up, the father of course, he has the same
property, he fits alone in the boat.
And the two daughters fit together or separately.
The text only says, “can carry a single
adult or up to two children”.
So, this kind of implies that 1 child can
also-, or one daughter can also cross by herself.
Which is definitely going to be necessary
in order to solve the puzzle.
Then, we have the information about where
everybody ends up.
The fisherman should end up in the starting
side.
Same with the boat.
And the father and daughters end up on the
other side.
And that is our graph basically.
This contains all the information that is
important to the story.
We have our actors: we have the father, the
two twin daughters, the fisherman, the boat,
where are they going to end up.
And who can fit into the boat at the same
time.
Crossing the river could also be modeled here
but it is not strictly necessary.
Like I said, your graph might end up very
differently to mine.